So other people want to honor them too. Each inductee tonight will get a
proclamation
available on wallpaper or room. We have a proclamation for the inductees from
Cleveland
Mayor Frank Jackson, Cleveland City Council, courtesy of the Council of Zone,
Ohio State
Senator Tom Catton, Governor John Kasich, Congresswoman Marzia Fudge, Congresswoman
Marzia
Fatter, Senator Rob Portman, Senator Sherrod Brown, Congressman David Joyce,
State Auditor
David Yost, County Executive Armand Boudish, and Ohio Attorney General Mike DeWine.
So
all of you, you're one of the first graduating students in the district of Ohio.
You'll also
receive your official Cleveland International Hall of Fame lapel pin. You'll
see a lot of
the inductees wearing that and you'll get your award. So what happens is we
call up the
inductor, gives the remarks, not a bio, that's in the book and on the web page.
The inductor
then gives you awards for the inductee, they post for the photos, looking at
ads first,
and the new Hall of Fame will speak. So let's get started, tell me when you
want to get the
ball rolling.
It is such a great honor to see all of you here for the eighth induction of the
Cleveland
International Hall of Fame and I am thrilled to be able to start this with
inviting August
Coos to come up here. August is going to induct Phil Miller and in this case,
his wife, Mariah.
August Coos himself was inducted into the inaugural class of the Hall of Fame
back in 2010.
His long career as ethnic affairs international relations advisor and leader
started with
Cleveland mayors, then the governors, then the senators and eventually
President George W. Bush.
He has earned more awards and recognitions than we can count on, including the
Citizen diplomat from the National Council for International Visitors. My
pleasure to
introduce to you my friend, August Coos.
Hello Cleveland people.
This is the picture of how the rest of the world should see what good see,
Cleveland City is all about.
Cleveland people and the reflection of this Cleveland people, it's right here
at the podium
today. These are the tools that we can put together and call it Cleveland
Museum.
This is the work of art for Cleveland.
And today when we talk about Cleveland people, let's go back two decades or
more
to remember how we have met each other. Where were we when we met each other?
And who was the person who introduced us to different cultures and different
people?
And was he the one who wrote about us and if we did not know how we have to do
it with his
column in a theater, we learned about events where and how we hope. He was the
one who made us
knowing each other and learn about our place in the city of history, our
neighborhood, our churches,
our community. But to look at that, not only that he was a lifelong promoter of
Cleveland
and the one who knew Cleveland very well, I would like to paint two little
pictures of
Bill Miller which illustrates so much of the man he was. Remember our own
National Festival?
They started right here in the front of this building and a mall between this
hotel and City Hall.
He was the master of ceremonies. He knew the people and we listened to people
coming on the
stage and listened to accordioners, tambourines, sitars, trumpets, and of
course a lot of everything
else, pipes and drums. So there he was introducing the people of Cleveland to
the people of Cleveland.
But they're not comparing to what he did in downtown in Playhouse Square on the
top of the stage
of State Theater. This is where he introduced the groups, the best of our
performing groups
on the stage where he played an important role of preserving state theater and
theaters in Playhouse
Square with the leader of the game, the pride of Cleveland and some of the best
theaters in the
nation. He did it because he saved and worked on a theater restoration,
preservation of theaters.
He knew the people and people who came to the stage performed what Cleveland
was to the best.
It was a colleague presentation of Cleveland. But to know Bill Miller in a
personal site,
especially as our dear and my dear friend, let's go back to summer festivals in
Cleveland,
neighborhood, church, community festivals. And oh yeah, of course, there were
beer festivals.
Picture this, October fest, beer festival. And before all the dignitaries came
on the stage,
there was Bill Miller right in the front stage. Before all the judges, mayors,
the
governors, even the president came on the stage, there was Bill Miller. In one
hand,
he had the beer sign. Another hand, he took off his hat. He put it over his
heart
and started singing God Bless America. That was our anthem. God bless America.
And today,
that blessing is also with us. And we'd like to, on behalf of all of us, show
our appreciation
and our gratitude to Mary Ann Miller, representing the family, Mark Miller, her
son.
That on behalf of all of us, we can extend our sincere gratitude and
congratulations
to the family and to remember Bill Miller with God Bless America and to us,
people of Cleveland.
God bless you. Mary Ann Miller.
Okay, look this way, please. Over this way.
Two days.
My Yana Shazi, we love you.
[laughter]
Turn to your Lord.
There we go.
And then straight across.
Anybody else?
[laughter]
[applause]
Okay, yes, let's do it.
They sprinted on me very fast. I didn't know the first point. But, anyway,
thank you for all this wonderful, warm interaction.
I can actually feel, feel, feel smiling. You would have been so proud. And
thank you, this whole organization, especially Debbie Hansen, for this
wonderful event and for this honor.
I feel very privileged to accept this fulfill. You would have been so proud.
Thank you very much.
Thank you all for coming. And I have met some people again tonight that I haven't
been for 20 years. It was wonderful.
It was just so great to see all of you again. And thank you for coming. And I
also want to thank the organization for making this possible and all the work
they do, especially Debbie Hansen.
And I want to thank my late friends for coming. And my son, Mark, and his
beautiful lady, Mary. And Mark just came here to settle for a new life in
Cleveland.
We work in Seattle. And I appreciate all your love and your support. Thank you
so much. The other time for making this in New York, but he's here in spirit.
And yes, Billy, we love you too. Anyway, and last but not least, I want to
thank all of the others in that piece tonight.
Congratulations. And I met some of you and the wonderful people. And they do a
great job. So thank you for everything. And please enjoy the rest of the
evening.
Because I'm the first.
I'm not going to make comments on each of the people. I do have to say
something because it's Bill's story. And I wrote about it in the book.
But the last time that I saw Bill Miller was at a party in a market one through
a supermarket out there somewhere.
But it was a holiday party. And he saw me and he put his arm around me and
started to sing Danny Boy. He sang a whole song.
Just belted it out top of his lungs and everyone just stood and watched and
applauded. And that was Bill Miller. He just he was a man of the people.
And there won't be another one like him. So this one.